So far, we've checked how well our models are
我们已经根据损失在每个周期的变化情况
performing based on how the loss changes over each epoch.
检查了模型的表现效果
But the exact number of epochs to train for is often hard to determine.
但是通常很难判断到底要训练多少个周期
How many epochs should you train for so that your network
才能使模型很准确
is accurate but it's not overfitting the training data?
并且不会过拟合训练数据
One method that's used in practice involves breaking the dataset into
实践中用到的一种方法是
three sets called training validation and test sets.
将数据集分成三部分：训练集、验证集和测试集
Each is treated separately by the model.
模型会单独处理每个数据集
The model looks only at the training set when it's
模型在训练并判断如何修改权重的过程中
actively training and deciding how to modify its weights.
仅查看训练集
After every training epoch,
每个训练周期之后
we check how the model is doing by looking at
我们通过查看训练损失和验证损失
the training loss and the loss on the validation set.
判断模型的表现效果
But it's important to note that the model does not use
但是需要注意的是 模型在反向传播过程中
any part of the validation set for the back propagation step.
不会使用验证集中的任何数据
We use this training set to find all the patterns we can,
我们使用训练集尽可能发现所有规律
and to update and determine the weights of our model.
并更新和确定模型权重
The validation set only tells us if that model is doing well on the validation set.
验证集只是告诉我们模型在验证集上表现是否不错
In this way gives us an idea of how well the model
这样我们就能判断
generalizes to a set of data that is separate from the training set.
模型在泛化到训练集之外的数据时效果如何
The idea is, since the model doesn't use the validation set for deciding its weights,
因为模型在确定权重时没有使用验证集
that it can tell us if we're overfitting the training set of data.
所以可以告诉我们模型是否过拟合训练集中的数据
Finally, the test set of data is saved for checking
训练模型之后
the accuracy of the model after it's trained.
使用测试集检查模型的准确率
This may be easiest to see in an example.
举个例子
Say it's at the model to train for 200 epochs,
假设模型训练了 200 个周期
and around epoch 100,
在第 100 个周期左右
you notice that the training loss starts
训练损失开始下降
decreasing but the validation loss is actually starting to increase.
但是验证损失开始上升
This actually indicates that the model is overfitting the training data because it's
表明模型过拟合训练数据了
not generalizing well enough to also perform well on the validation set.
因为它不能足够地泛化并在验证集上也表现很好
So, if you see this divide and how the training and validation losses decrease,
如果你看到这种训练损失和验证损失变化情况
you'll want to stop changing the weights of your network around epoch 100 and
需要在第 100 个周期左右停止更改网络权重
ignore or throw away the weights from later epochs where there's evidence of overfitting.
并忽略或丢弃后续周期中的权重 因为有证据表明后面开始过拟合了
This process can also prove useful if we
如果我们有多个潜在结构可以选择
have multiple potential architectures to choose from.
这个流程也很有用
For example, if you're deciding on the number of layers to put in the model,
例如 如果你需要决定向模型中添加多少个层级
then you'll want to save the weights from
首先需要保存每个潜在结构的权重
each potential architecture for later comparison,
以便稍后加以比较
and can choose to pick the model that gets the lowest validation loss.
并选择验证损失最低的模型
You might be wondering why must we create a third dataset.
你可能会不理解为何要创建第三个数据集？
Couldn't we just use the test set for this purpose?
为何不直接使用测试集？
Well, the idea is that when we go to test the model,
这是因为在测试模型时
it looks at data that it has truly never seen before.
必须使用模型之前从未见过的数据
Even though the model doesn't use the validation set to update its weights,
虽然模型不使用验证集更新权重
our model selection process is based on how the model
但是我们在选择模型时
performs on both the training and validation sets.
依据的是模型在训练集和验证集上的表现
So, in the end, the model is biased in favor of the validation set.
所以最终模型会偏向于验证集
Thus, we need a separate test set of data to truly see how
我们需要一个单独的测试数据集
our selected model generalizes and performs when
才能真正了解所选的模型
given data it really has not seen before.
在之前确实未见过的数据上泛化效果如何
In the next video, I'll show you how to use
在下个视频中 我将演示
these ideas to fine tune your network architecture
如何根据这些技巧微调网络结构